#### Contact

ggitechno@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ulucanibrahim (LinkedIn) www.idiap.ch/~iulucan/ (Company) orcid.org/0000-0001-6821-8709 (Other)

### Top Skills

Large Language Models (LLM)
ArcGIS Pro
Object Detection

## Languages

Turkish (Native or Bilingual)
French (Limited Working)
English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Kaggle Python Coder

Research - Text Analysis with Transformers and LLMs in Python

BIOMETRICS WORKSHOP

edX Verified Certificate for Python Basics for Data Science

TensorFlow

# Ibrahim Ulucan

Data Scientist || GIS Software Specialist

Lausanne, Vaud, Switzerland

## Summary

Interest in GIS software, Research, Al Applications.

All my professional and educational life, I have had many opportunities to work in many different countries in a multinational environment for more than 10 years. Meanwhile, I am always enthusiastic about continuing to improve myself in the field of "Data Science" by keeping in touch with the academic environment.

## Experience

Idiap Research Institute
Research Assistant
December 2023 - Present (1 year 11 months)
Switzerland

Biometrics Security and Privacy (BSP) Group

Applying Machine Learning Algorithms by using Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit Learn, Keras, Tensorflow and other Python Libraries.

Sitemark

Belaium

Data Engineer March 2020 - December 2022 (2 years 10 months)

**Data Scientist** 

Ministry of National Defence GIS Software Specialist 2014 - 2019 (5 years) Turkey

Geographic Information Systems (GIS)

NATO Imagery Analyst 2013 - 2014 (1 year) Ministry of National Defence Electronic Engineer 2005 - 2013 (8 years) Turkey

# Education

University of Lausanne - UNIL French Language and Literature · (September 2022 - January 2024)

Orta Doğu Teknik Üniversitesi / Middle East Technical University Information Technology - GGIT, Master of Science · (February 2018 - July 2021)

Orta Doğu Teknik Üniversitesi / Middle East Technical University Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Information Technology · (August 2021)

Boğaziçi University Bachelor's degree, Préparation

Science High School (Antalya) High School Diploma